Firstly, making predictions in the pre-listening is
really important.
You have to predict the paraphrases of the
keywords in the options.
By doing this, you will listen in a
more attentive and active way to find the answers.
Remember to check the answers to avoid
unnecessary mistakes and never leave your answer sheet blank.
Secondly, about note-taking.
When handling questions of matching information in section
2, you have to take notes next to the options.
For these questions in section 3, you should
draw a table to take notes.
For example, these are my notes for the
first exercise that we did for matching information
in section 2 about student volunteers.
And for the matching information exercise in section
3, we will take notes in a zig
-zag order, using a table, just like how
we do it for multiple-choice questions in
section 3 that we learned in a previous
lesson.
This is an example of how we can
take notes while listening to the recording about
the two students discussing
their presentation.
Now that you understand these key strategies for
matching information questions, keep practicing to build your
confidence and improve your listening skills.